welcome back to our new video or last one. Now we have go through the all the
internet local to local land network okay but what about the external work okay
so we are going to discuss internal versus external network in this video
here we are going to talk about the internet, external internet, VPNs and the
benefit of them, limitations of the infrastructure of them everything. Let's
start. What is internet? Internet is a private network owned by a single
organization a design to facilitate secure collaboration and communication
exclusively among its employees. It acts as an internal hub for information
application and services accessible only to apply as personal within the
company firewall. Now within the company everything you have it's internet
everything you file server or anything is your internet. Come back to the
Washington Net. Internet have limited number of contributors making them
highly secure and less expectable to external others. The prefix
intro signified it's internal within nature, advantage of internet and decide
advantage. It's in his communication and centralize information and decide
what is maintenance code because you have to maintain locally. Everything you
server whatever you have hosted in your local so you have to maintain cost
and limited accessibility because there is a limited number of people can
access within the network not from the outside or anyone. Now extend your
reach. What is the external? Extrend is a private network that leverage
internal technology to provide control access to external products such as
partners, suppliers, vendor, customer, it is essential and extended version
of organization internet allows secure authorized communication and data
setting we got the company we did. Internal boundaries. I was trying to read
everything in a one breath but I'm not able to do. The external enable
single-school version with the author of cyber making it a critical tool for
a business that need to share information equally with their ecosystem while
maintaining control over the internal data. Now external net is used because
let us assume there is a scenario in which there is a vendor there is a
what is a vendor. No vendor, vendor is the one which will help you to compute
which are okay. Now there is a vendor in your company. He have some
resources like PDF. He want to share it with you and you in an internet
a private internet. You can say internet. Now how can he send you data and how
you can access it safely? That where action it comes we will give him a
zone space fix zone okay. Now here he comes and put his data his PDF his
resources and from the internet we access their zone safely and we get to
see it. It's that simple okay. Let us assume there is a box in which a vendor
comes put his files and then we come from our company and take those files
that's it. Advanced is improved collaboration and secret data
setting is there. This one is a complex database setting that zone is
complex and there is a secret is always but you have to make up to go through
that secret is good. You have to make black proper policy in a firewall. There's a
difference between them so that's not asked by the way just go through the
difference and it it's okay but however you can say that it's for saying
information through within the organization it is between the internal
external one by single organization one by single of a development as security
implemented of your firewall so currently implemented we have variable
separating from the internet and it's by managing the single of nature
so I'm the number of connected device private network type of organization
desktop and platform machine network and limited and compromised version
of external here connected device comfortable with internet but external
private network is public network for sharing formation because it is in a
public zone so that's a public network we are using here and used to check
the status status and mail place order sector and I'm gonna come to watch
version of internet now what is a weapon everyone knows what's a private
everyone know we depend on it but no but not how it works so it is it's
simply a secret encrypted connection over public network just like IP
signal it's ever encrypted secret tunnel over the public network such as
internet so in the internet you have a private internet okay which is secret
encrypted and you are going to use that internet not anyone else we've been
secret to your internet advocate marks your eye only identity make it
significantly harder for third parties to track your activities but to set your
data this encryption occurring real-time provide a limited production
now how it works so it operate by a routing your IP address through the mode
server managed by the VPN host when you browse online with a VPN you can
set or become the origin of a data yes when you browse it will become the
origin of a data instead of you so it prevent your ISP and other entities
from Martin your own website so what will you open that so when you're using
some website using a VPN instead of your IP instead of your location
instead of your ISP provider yeah it go the traffic nested from the VPN host so
everything is from your end is safe now there is a different type of events
actually there's a lot of type of VPNs we have but we're going to discuss
setups side-to-side VPN which is connected to two locations and in which each site is
have encrypted data and and other side have a decrepit to more access VPN
enable individual remote address to SQL access the component network VPN as a
services cloud VPN hosted in a cloud interface where client traffic internet
internet from the cloud state of look at is commonly used for consumer for
production of public traffic and continuity this of benefits security is
there simplification of access control is there and VPs you have to go up
to provide security privacy guarantees so there's a confidence to say
integrity and authentication is there as well as the limitation is there
fragment of visibility is there we can get point-to-point connection making it
challenging for security to maintain combination of visibility for 50
threats and response that's why when most of the companies a VPN is not allowed
even though you can't open the in common to more new browser no integrated
security is there no efficient routing is there poor security is because
there's a large number of people has come going to use that poor that VPN then
definitely that traffic initiated server get congested and you cannot you
could have to choose with other server of other countries in a VPN so
sometime you said that check that when you try to connect with a VPN you
get failed because there is a lot of people in there so it's covered is
not that good in this and in front of everybody so so compromised in
point-to-point can get a threat full access to a VPN is also supposing a
signal is recorded therefore there is a limitation and security is called with
it not also we we can protocol is a point-to-point and land to be later
telling protocol hi-psec and also open VPN as you can see it's dependent on
the speed basically a secure order you have to just note it down that what
everything works how it works now it's not that important but you have to
understand ike we do internet cakes and we do how it works and the what is the
advantage it's over the where God and now you know internet extraordinary VPN
now moved to next must you network psychology the farable as you heard of my
time that I mentioned fireballs but how it works now we will talk about this
this is in the presentation we will go through the state of drug fireballs from
there for basic consent to advance corporate is like team it right zone the zone
I'm talking about you will learn how firewall inspect traffic they were a
steps and if you're in critical load they play in the product in place less
from the both external and tender threat we will also cover the advantage and
disadvantage of implement a firewall and they have to be coming with the knowledge
of making making form decision about no security so what is a firewall firewall
is the gatekeeper a dislicator keeper marting on incoming and
or wing or wing of traffic based on the pretty different sets of security rules
it decided with their accept or reject or drop specific traffic this make it as
a support for today connected no one much they've got your distal but from
and one of a step research so every every company have their fireballs to protect
the traffic whatever the traffic is going through it depending on the policies
depending on the complication they're on the firewall we can accept the traffic
and drop the traffic or block the traffic completely now firewall
inspect and authenticate data packet in a real time this in work checking the
data packet against the different criteria to determine whether it's
supposed as well if it will to meet the criteria the firewall block it from
the integral leveling leaving that network okay so it will
block either from leaving the network it is a malicious or entering the
network if it smelches now the types of firewall is important it will do as
always up to in-home network in interview so it's a packet filled in firewall
proxy service firewall and exit it's a firewall and it's filled with inspection
firewall and lies a small amount of data packet database on the header
information packet filtering is there take it or proxy service
forever it is an activity expecting for if it's a deeper level so there is a
inspection is going on on a table over it break the connection between the
sender and reset activity have for both which provide enhanced recorded
providing by making the internal network now stay full in inspection firewall
monitor active connection dynamically a loop along a blocking traffic based
on the connection state this over from more robust recorded than packet
filtering by understanding the context of it from now using this firewall it
combine the trace and fair features and it once gave it like deep packet
inspection packet capturing is there interesting IPS and IDs it doesn't
prevent system and present detection system and so it delivers third intelligent
to provide some specific security how it works there's a packet filtering is
there as we go through each packet and each check for legitimate or not source
and destination IP poor number protocol it compares this data against the pay
different rules should be determined whether to allow proof that state full
inspection is always happened but we can disable the debt as well some time
it is a certificate inspection as well so it's all depend on the
communication you do from your side so what is a certificate what is a
stateful and what is a deep inspection is all you have to go through say just
for a little bit basic when certificate inspection which if you have your
system have a certificate then only you get you can able to go through the
firewall else you you did not get any internet how in a deep inspection every
every packet you send is going to be expected in a stateful not everything but
air closure one is going to be inspect advance firewall keep track of the state
of active session this meant the firewall your mother set of decision and allow
packet data part of a service connection while blocking and
allocated incoming traffic day you will get the behavior of data
packet and it connects a catalog pattern to improve vision third word
also what is it DPA deep packet inspection yes some variable in per DPA which goes
when to just resume header the inspect the payload of like a tune as they
contain these can be allowed them to identify specific application detect
but it is such a smart word malicious but it is based on this measure what is a
firewall officer even if it's a firewall continuous log activity and make
critical decision about traffic this ongoing process of waiting for meeting
drug integrity and respond to potential threats so logging and let's
important because sometime we have to do audit sometime we have to find out
that is this connection but the connection is made through this system for that
logging is important and for alert is help else to identify that we are not
able to always 24 by 7 in the front of our firewall so alert is the one that
help us to identify that okay it's at this moment of 10 this occurs as it's a
uptillization of memory utilization or some a big traffic is going on
through our ISP's our network so this is how it works so it log all the
traffic that password data language packet were allowed to
blow they can generate alerts for this very activity of policy what is
an in-living network administrator is one calculator potential these logs are
invaluable for trading it's a risk point for density cluster so based on that
decision it make either is all out we will allow a block we will completely
block it or drop if it matches a deny route or a neural it discarded without
any line making it a bit as a destination host is at reachable but it's a
flag some packets may be flagged for the inspection or
analysis by other security to like introducing to access so the packet will
go but it will be flagged as it it may be a false so it will
code for an analysis what is the advantage so production
authorization unauthorized accesses get increased control
of network and access localization complacence is their
prevention of malware another threat monitoring of networking to the
network networks emergency what is a network segmentation
so I am telling only the things that I think that you need to understand
everything is monitoring of network activity you can go through
the line and you can easily able to understand
publish a compilation compiler and see you know
control of network analysis you know but what is a network segment is a network
segment it's like providing over a beginner to
into a smaller network so that there is a less amount of
less amount of traffic inspection is there and if someone
able to breach than your firewall or your network you still able to handle the
other segmentations because of one segment get
attack birth other segment is still have a chances to prevent and
stay there still secure so fragmentation is very important and it is done
in the firewall side even in the code three we can do
so disadvantage of physical complexity is the maintaining and
adding the policy and everything is going from the firewall
then it's very crucial to configure and it's very hard to configure
due to a visibility in the firewall sometimes you have to pay
add-on like an laser or log-in laser a lot of things you have to pay
for that to get a more visibility in your every packet every
thing however on the basic setup you don't get that logs log
don't get that audit or there's a no don't also get a
that is a chain reduction that who is changing what or is there any alert
like so you get a basic thing for sense of security limited
edibility is there a performance impact here's limited
stability and then number of so develop the firewall you have
skill register positive and because if it is able to do that
let us in that you using because around five thousand six thousand
employees you have in a company and using a
medieval level of firewall then it make a session if it
it will increase the memory and synthesize the it will also get down
depending on the model if the scalability is dependent
you have to be you can support sometimes you can support is not
supported but sometime we measure the firewall type you say
we have been is there cost her depending on the model
depending on the feature it had cost is including
what is the DMC zone so DMC zone is a physical or physical sub network
that contain x versus N of nature is an external facing
services to and understand it work definitely the
attack is an intermediate analytic perfect service from the
socio tender network this add extra level security
proven direct on critical internal resource key characteristic of
BMG isolation is there because it's outside your internet
and so it's if anything happens there they you would
private internet is secure so DMC server is a powerful zone
between the general working external to produce the risk of
barrier attack on sensitive internal resources public access
there firewall production is there firewall are typically used to control
the traffic between the DMC and the digital network and they did not
allow only specific types of traffic so in firewall when we are making the
policy we can we can mention that that this IP
from the source can go through the DMG to destination on this port
so VA on the firewall we can manage all these things
on the basis of that it is managed and it is secure
benefits of DMG what is a key characteristic it is
improved security control access there and simplified management
however the complexity is also involved while it's
structuring the DMC while the stability stability there's a
complexity but after once we can easily simplify the management
let's move it when do we use DMG when we're hosting some
services in a public domain we want security as well and there's a
violence awful vendor and there is a regular compliance form
security standards and for the audit testing and deployment
for is also we have to do before deploying and after the
pipeline to prevent any power potentially back all on
sensitivity of recent so that it from the DMG no one enter the
internal network now DMG architecture the type of
electrical DMG architecture involved multiple layer of security
tensor robust for example take it too firewall
more firewall position between the internet and the DMG and the other
between DMG and the internal network this get a layer difference
making it harder to attack it but in trade
definitely this is how it actually works in our companies
sometime in a company they use only for firewall and it is also
possible public facing servers server located with the DMG itself
these server host service such as web server email server during the server
if a server which need to be extended from the
data internal network the only citizen prior network contain
sensitive data and critical resource service image protocol remains
productive and isolated from the direct internet exposure by the second
firewall how a second firewall is not always the
important work firewall is enough to make sure
you have a good policy on which the traffic is going to connect with the DMG
and come back from DMG to local that's all
what is the advantage and disadvantage of this no advantage at
the in in security control access there risk of my irrigation is a
simplified management of quality complex existing environment is there
this one a complexity is there higher cost he has definitely missed
configuration which is just a limited production if you do not have
adding much good policies and there's always a
yes zero double but it is a probability in which
it is a type of bug we can say that there's no one know that
it is a first time it get explored so no one know that what will it will be
it can be anything okay so maintenance over it
that's it for the now now we as you can see there the firewall
individual for the nervous equity acting is essential gatekeeper you can say
in an interview essential they still gatekeeper DNG
prior and additionally of difference for the public facing services
the services we have to put in a public domain that can be accessed from the
internet work and the event there as well both require careful planning and
going management to be effective yes before doing anything
we have to make up properly so this is all this is all
all about in this course let me know if you want a deep dive course on this
in which i'm going to use everything not only a pdf
i'm going to do make a diagram just like i did in one of our video
to in a topology video i make a diagram to understand you
that to make you understand that how these things work so if you want that
just come and out and i will make a detailed video on network
however i can also have expertise in cyber security so if you want a
separate course of cyber security i can do that as well so that's it thank you very much
and i need your love just show me with your love thank you